Guide to the Laura (Riding) Jackson and Schuyler B. Jackson collection, 1924-1991
Jackson, Laura (Riding) and Schuyler B., 1924-1991
- Series IV. Literary Manuscripts
  - Published Works
    - Essays and Articles
      - "Postscript to attached article" The Private Library, no. 5 (Autumn, 1972) pp. 139-146; ts. 7pp. (Box 83, Folder 15)
      - "Letter at Year's End, Year's Beginning, 1974-1975 For My Friends" Some Communications of Broad Reference (Northridge, Ca.: Lord John Press, 1983) ts. 6pp. (Box 83, Folder 16)
      - "A Letter For Everyone. End of the Year, 1975" Chelsea 35 (1976) and Some Communications of Broad Reference (Northridge, Ca.: Lord John Press, 1983) ts. 2pp. (Box 83, Folder 17)
      - "An assumption that is ... " [published as: "Twentieth-Century Literary Individualism,"] Chelsea 35 (1976) ts. 4pp; ts. 4pp. carbon (Box 83, Folder 18)
      - "Neglected books" Antaeus, 20 (Winter 1976) ts. 3pp. photocopy; postscript ts. 1p.; ts. 3pp. photocopy (Box 83, Folder 19)
      - "For A Birthday" Some Communications of Broad Reference (Northridge, Ca.: Lord John Press, 1983) (Box 83, Folder 20)
      - [Corrections for the Sulfur 10 printing of "Engaging in the Impossible" Sulfur 10 (1984)] ts. 3pp. (Box 83, Folder 21)
      - "...concerned with a 'good' of its peculiar own" ts. pp. 4-17 [fragment from "Is There a World for Literature, Is There Literature for a World" Chelsea, 44 (1985)] (Box 83, Folder 22)
      - "Twentieth Century Change in the Idea of Poetry, and of the Poet, and of the Human Being" PN Review 57 (Spring 1986) ts. 71pp.; ts. 70pp. carbon; notes for revision (Box 83, Folder 23)
      - "Response to Mr. Norris" Language and Style 19 (Spring 1986) ts. pp. 1-6 (Box 83, Folder 24)
      - "Introduction to a Book of Later-Life Commentaries" Sulfur, 20 (Fall 1987) ts. 23pp. (Box 83, Folder 25)
      - "Judgement of One Another" Chelsea, 52 (1991) ts. 1p.; ts. 1p.; ts. 1p. carbon (Box 83, Folder 26)
      - "The Only Possible Ending" PN Review 78 (March/April 1991) ts. pp.1-4 (Box 83, Folder 27)
      - "On C. M. Doughty" PN Review, no. 25 ts. 21pp. carbon (Box 83, Folder 28)
      - "The Human and the Universal" in Laura (Riding) Jackson and the Promise of Language by Margaret Nichols (Cornell University Library. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections: 1998)[early draft] ts. 7pp. [first draft] ms./ts. 8pp [2nd draft] ts. 6pp. ts. 5pp. ts. 6pp. [Sept. 1989] assorted additions/fragments ms. 4pp.; ms.2pp.; ms. 2pp.; ts.2pp. (Box 83, Folder 29)
    - Letters to Editors
      - Americans Abroad: An Anthology ed. by Peter Neagoe (The Hague: Servire Press, 1932) pp. ?-327, cutting (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Minnesota Review, Vol. XII, No. 1, 1967, pp. 77-79, clipping (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The New York times Book Review, November 24, 1968, n.p., clipping (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The Observer, October 3, 1970, n.p., clipping (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The Observer, October 1970 [published October 18, 1970] ts. 2pp.; ts. 2pp. photocopy; ts. 3pp; clipping (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The Times Literary Supplement, Nov. 3, 1972, 2ts. 1p. photocopy (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The Private Library, Autumn 1973, ts. pp. 1-12; + note ms. 1p. (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The Nation, December 30, 1974, ts. 3pp.; ts. 3pp. carbon; March 22, 1975, p. 322, clipping; photocopy of clipping; includes photocopy of review to which she responded (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The New York Review of Books, Aug. 4, 1975, ts. 4pp. carbon; ts. 4pp. photocopy (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The New York Review of Books, Aug. 27, 1975, ts. 3pp. carbon [published October 7, 1975] (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The New York Review of Books, October 2, 1975, n.p., clipping, April 19, 1976, ts. 2pp. (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The New York Review of Books, April 19, 1976, ts. 2pp. (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The New York Review of Books, April 29, 1976, n.p., clipping and two photocopies (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The National Review, June 10, 1976, ts. 1p [incomplete]; clipping; note ms. 1p. (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Cite AB, December 1, 1980, p. 364, clipping (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The Times Literary Supplement, July 16, 1982, n.p., photocopy (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The New York Review of Books, Aug. 12, 1982, n.p., clipping (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Sulfur, July 1983, ts. 3pp.; note ms. 1p. (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - The Cornell Alumni News, October 1983, pp. 10-16 [entire issue] ts. 4pp. + ts. letter to Editor, July 23, 1983 (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Cornell Alumni News, October 17, 1983, ts. 1p; clipping, pp. 15-16; includes letter ms. 1p. March 6, 1984 (Box 84, Folder 2)
      - The New York Review of Books, Dec. 22, 1983, n.p., clipping; photocopy (Box 84, Folder 2)
      - The New York Review of Books, January 31, 1985, p. 41, clipping (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Editorial Activities
      - Focus, Issues I-IV, Jan.-Dec. 1935, "Notes to accompany the four issues of Focus held by the Department of Rare Books, Cornell University Library" ts. 1p. carbon; "Focus" ts. 1p., June 10, 1976 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Unpublished Works
    - Book-length Projects
      - Dictionary of Related Meaning, "Old Dictionary Labors...My Formal Statements on the 'Dictionary' on which the coming of agreement between Dent & Co. and Little, Brown, & Co. was based" [front and back cover of the original folder ms. 2pp.] "Appendix matter" ms. 1p. July 1964 "Dictionary of Exact Meanings: Explanation" ts. 16pp. [For the publisher] "Americanisms" ts. 10pp. [untitled] ts. 5pp. "The Index" ts. 3pp. "The Latest in Synonymy" by Schuyler and Laura Jackson Wilson Library Bulletin, 17 (November, 1942), pp. 219-225, clipping "Plans for Work" by Schuyler and Laura Jackson, October 12, 1941, ts. 7pp. + insert ms. 1p. "A Sample Set of Definitions and Word-groups from A Working English Dictionary and Thesaurus" ts. 1p. "Dictionary" ts. 28pp. + title page "Thesaurus" ts. pp. 1-12 + title page "Index" ts. 18pp. "Some groups" ts. 1p. + ts. 1p. photocopy; pp. 14-5 carbon; ts. p. 15 photocopy "Index" ts. 5pp. "Meanings" ts. pp. 5-17, carbon (Box 84, Folder 4)
      - ["Doughty books"], [Background material on Doughty] Passage from Arabia Deserta? ts 1p.; "Transcription of notes by John Freeman (1880-1929), ca. 1920" ts. 1p.; letter from Charles M. Doughty to John Freeman?, Jan. 28, [19??] ts./ms. 2pp. photocopy; "On the Josteldal-brae [diacritics omitted] in Norway, With Some General Remarks and a Plate by C. M. Doughty" London, 1866, pp. 2-14, photocopy; clipping from TLS, August 21, 1981 (Box 84, Folder 5)
      - "Barker Fairly on Doughty" ts. 26pp.; ms. 4pp. (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - Herbert Davis, "Charles Doughty, 1843-1926" [Bergen lecture, Yale University, Nov. 23, 1943] photocopy (Box 84, Folder 7)
      - "John Holloway on Charles M. Doughty" ts. 25pp. (Box 84, Folder 8)
      - L(R)J to ? ts. 3pp. n.d. (Box 84, Folder 9)
      - map for Dawn in Britain ms. 1p.; ms. 1p. carbon; ms. 1p. magic marker (Box 84, Folder 10)
      - "The Dawn in Britain: [The Outermost Isle] Reproduced (line-by-line--but without metre) in the English of our time" Part I ms. 150 pp. (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - "The Dawn in Britain" Part II ms. pp. 151-236 (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - "The Dawn in Britain" 3ts. pp. 20-69 (Box 85, Folder 3)
      - "The Dawn in Britain" 3ts. pp. 70-107 (Box 85, Folder 4)
      - "A Lexicographical Complement to The Dawn in Britain by Charles M. Doughty, Compiled by Schuyler [B.] Jackson "Explanatory note "The Glossary for The Dawn in Britain" [originally compiled for the Department of Rare Books, Cornell University] by L(R)J, June 18, 1970, Wabasso, FLA] ms. 1p. [Title page] (photocopy of badly damaged page) "Additions, revisions [by S.B.J] to accompany manuscript" ms. 8pp [glossary] ms. pp.1-196 (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - "A Lexicographical Complement to The Dawn in Britain by Charles M. Doughty, Compiled by Schuyler [B.] Jackson Wabasso, FLA" A-Kn ts. pp. 1-95 (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - [Lexicographical Complement] Kn-Tr ts. pp. 95-184 (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - [Lexicographical Complement] Tr-End ts. pp. 185-208 (Box 86, Folder 4)
      - [corrections for "Doughty book" addressed to Michael Kirkham], ms. 25pp., Feb. 10-15, 1971 [notes, title sheet, dedication, table of contents, foreword] ms 12pp. "Foreword" ts. 3pp.; ms. 1p. "From old draft of Introduction" ms. pp. 28-35 "From an early draft of Introduction" ms. pp. 11-15 "Explanatory Essay" ms. 25pp. Ch. 2 ms. 7+25pp. Ch. 3 ms. 39pp. (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - ["Doughty book"] Ch. 4 ms. 52pp.; Appendix ms. 36pp. ["Notes on Doughty books," Jan. 1969] ms. 18 3x5 cards (1969) (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - "Original Doughty File" [concordance file], n.d., ca. 300 3x5 cards (Box 87)
      - "Concordance of Names used in The Dawn in Britain of Charles M. Doughty" + various cards and notes, n.d., ca. 300 3x5 cards (Box 88)
      - "Names not yet entered in DIB concordance" and additional cards, n.d., ca. 300 3x5 cards (Box 89)
      - "Original Doughty File," cont., n.d., [Concordance file] ca. 300 3x5 cards (Box 90)
      - "Original Doughty File," cont., n.d., [Concordance file] ca. 150 3x5 cards (Box 91, Folder 1-6)
      - Clippings and miscellaneous notes on language and includes "... a rebellion against modes of thinking..." ms. pp. 6-24, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - "The Right English of Charles M. Doughty by Laura (Riding) Jackson for Schuyler B. Jackson" n.d., [introductory matter] ts. vii+ pp.; [foreword] ts. vii + pp. [revisions] ts. pp. iv-vii Part I, The Story of a Devotion (1) ts. pp. 5-12 (2) Thoughts on Doughty by Schuyler B. Jackson ts. pp. 13-24 [additional copies of Parts I, II and carbon copies of Parts, I, II] Part II: Textual Illustration Introductory Comments ts. pp. 25-30; ts. pp. 25-30 carbon; revisions to p. 30 and other revisions for Part II (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - "The Right English of Charles M. Doughty..." n.d., Part III "The Whole Doughty" ts. 16pp.; ts. 16pp. carbon Part IV "A Path of Hope" ts. 40pp. with additional copies "As to Glossary for the Dawn of Britain" ts. pp. 3-7; ts. pp. 11-14; ts. pp. 1-4; revisions ts. n.p. "The Role of Truth in Doughty's Cosmos" ts. pp. 14-15 and assorted ts. pp. (Box 92, Folder 2)
      - Under the Mind's Watch, "Under the Mind's Watch: Concerning Issues of Language, Literature, and Life of Contemporary Bearing" by Laura (Riding) Jackson "Dedication," "Explanation," Preface," "Language," ms. 1p., ts. 199pp. (photocopy except pp. 183-183 carbon) (Box 92, Folder 3)
      - "Literature" ts. pp. 200-324 photocopy, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 4)
      - "The New Immorality" ts. pp. 325-461 photocopy, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - "Life" ts. pp. 462-596 photocopy, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2)
      - ["...from early writings...] ts. pp. 597-715 photocopy, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 3)
      - "Under the Mind's Watch, by Laura (Riding) Jackson. Prospectus" ts. 11pp photocopy "Homosexuality" ts. 21 pp. "Anti-Language sentiment in contemporary Literature Attitudes" ts. 2pp. carbon "For Finis" ts. 2pp.; 3 ts. 2pp.; 1 carbon copy [Interview cited by L(R)J in "Under the Mind's Watch" "Poet James Dickey on Carter"] clipping, 1977 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Poems
      - "In Gratuitous Witness" ts. 2pp. carbon, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 5)
      - "On Exactitude" ts. 1p.; note 2ts. 1p. carbon, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Short Essays and Notes
      - "The authors are at pains to try to shield Horace from suspicion..." ts. pp. 6-13 + notes ms. 2pp., n.d. (Box 93, Folder 7)
      - "As to myself and my work in connection with Robert Graves according to the Martin Seymour-Smith essay on Robert Graves in Contemporary Poets of the English Language" ts. pp. 1-14, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 8)
      - "As to 'What Next'?" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 93, Folder 9)
      - "Body and Mind and the Linguistic Ultimate" ts. 53pp; ts 53 pp. carbon; assorted ts. pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - "The Case Against and For My Thinking-Speaking Ways", n.d. (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - "Corrections for the essay 'Interest' ( The Massachusetts Review Vol XXIII, No. 3)" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 3)
      - "Corrections Needed in 'Backgrounds' ( Glasgow Review) ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 4)
      - "How It All Goes" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - "Inquiry Addressed To Whoever May Be Moved To Reply Be It Myself Alone" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 6)
      - "I wrote this poem in private reflection..." [commentary on Sonia Raiziss' introduction to the Chelsea Retrospective, 1984] "written as a private presentation to her", n.d. (Box 94, Folder 7)
      - "A Letter on Martin Seymour Smith's Public Treatment of the Subject of Myself" ts. 2pp.; ts. 2pp. carbon" [Further] to Someone on Martin Seymour-Smith" ts. 2pp., ts. 2pp. carbon, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 8)
      - "Language Attacked, Language Championed" ts. 4pp. (with additional pp. 3-4); ms. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 9)
      - [Language notes] ms. 1p.; ms. 2pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 10)
      - "Mathematics" [for Schuyler] ts. 3pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 11)
      - "My disposition To Others" ts. 5pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 12)
      - "My feelings about America in 1932..." ms. 1p. carbon; note ms. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 13)
      - "My interest in writing on my views of an earlier time..." ts. 1p.; 2ts. 1p. carbon, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 14)
      - "Notes for the Time of Ultimate Candor" ts. 2pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 15)
      - "Nothing Left But Everything" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 16)
      - "Omens of the Scene" ms. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 17)
      - "On the Continuing of the Continuing" ts. 13pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 18)
      - "Other Creatures Besides Ourselves Form Unions of Life-Activity..." ts. 5pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 19)
      - [Note concerning] "A Pamphlet Against Anthologies" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 20)
      - "A Picture of Truth in Our Time (The Century's Last Quarter)" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 21)
      - "Poetry As Image of Poetry" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 22)
      - "The Principle of the Thing" ts. 30pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 23)
      - "Sins in the Name of Literary Schlarship" ts. 21pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 24)
      - "Some Notes on My Poems For a Student of My Work..." ts. 3pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 25)
      - "Sorry: to have put in so much of my writing...", photocopy of ms. comments written by Laura Riding on the back of one of the pages in the typescript of Snakes and Ladders, which Katharine Burdekin submitted to the Seizin Press and attached to letter from Daphne Patai to Laura (Riding) Jackson, August 1, 1987.; See: Series III. Correspondence. Laura (Riding) Jackson, Incoming, Patai, Daphne, (Box 94, Folder 26)
      - "Speaking from Principle" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 27)
      - "Statement by Laura (Riding) Jackson upon the publication of T. S. Matthews' Jacks or Better..." 3ts. 4pp., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 28)
      - "The Story Itself is Alive" ts. 1p.; 2ts. 1p. carbon, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 29)
      - [Terence Diggory material] Commentary ts. 1p. "Chapter One: Introduction " ts. 4 pp. [untitled] ts. pp.218-231 "Notes" ts. pp. 289-290, 348-352, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 30)
      - "To a friend - comment on poets of the'twenties and thirties..." ts. 1p.; ts. 1p. carbon, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 31)
      - "To Someone as to a Certain Library Collection, to which he has a responsible relation" ts. 1p.; ts. 1p. carbon, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 32)
      - "Trials in the Definition of Singular Words" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 94, Folder 33)
      - "Wexler's 'Pursuit' of Laura (Riding) Jackson" [by James F. Mathias] note by L(R)J ms. 1p.; ts. 13pp.; ts. 13 pp. photocopy, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1)
      - "What I thought I had done..." [by L(R)J?] ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2)
      - "Written After Reading a University President's Reflections on Educational Ideals" ts. 1p., n.d. (Box 95, Folder 3)
      - "A View of Robert Graves" ts. 8pp. carbon; ts. 8 pp. phtocopy, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 4)
      - "Words spoken by the telephone to Joyce Wexler..." ts. 1p.; ts. 1p.; note ms. 1p., n.d. "14A. Communications. Supplementary questions..." enclosed with letter to Arthur Barker, Nov. 19, 1933 ms. 2pp., See: Series III. Correspondence. Outgoing, Barker, Arthur (Box 95, Folder 5)
      - [Galley proof of "New Year Notes" by James Reeves carrying notes by L(R)J] ms. 1p., ca. 1934 (Box 95, Folder 6)
      - [Galley proof of "Sirventes" by James Reeves (1930) and L(R)J's notes] ts. 1p.; ms. 2pp., ca. 1934 (Box 95, Folder 7)
      - "Saw Any Man Dead Sea--Paraphrase" ms. 1p., ca. 1934 "I was born in New York City..." enclosed with letter to Living Authors, Jul. 4, 1933, See: Series III. Correspondence. Outgoing, Living Authors (Box 95, Folder 8)
      - "C'an Torrent" ts. 2pp., 1935? "To the Endorsers of the Covenant of Literal Mortlity" ts. 4pp., Feb. 1939 (Box 95, Folder 9)
      - "Early Note on Poetry Re-Evaluated" ms. 2pp., 1950s or 1960s (Box 95, Folder 10)
      - "1964 commentary on Lives of Wives by author..." ms. 3x5 card; ms. 1p., 1964 (Box 95, Folder 11)
      - [note concerning...] Almost Forgotten Germany [work by Georg Schwarz, translated by Laura Riding and Robert Graves (Deya, Majorca: The Seizin Press; London: Constable & Co., 1936] ms. 3x5 card, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 12)
      - "Retrospective note on The World and Ourselves by the author, July 1964" ts. 1p. (Box 95, Folder 13)
      - [Note concerning] "No Trouble" by Len Lye (Deya, Majorca; The Seizin Press, 1930) ms. 3x5 card, Nov. 16, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 14)
      - "Proof copy of A Mistake Somewhere" ms. 3x5 card, Nov. 16, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 15)
      - "Proof copy of The Moon's No Fool" ms. 3x5 card, Nov. 16, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 16)
      - [Note concerning] "In a Café" ms. 3x5 card, Dec. 1964 (Box 95, Folder 17)
      - "A commentary of 1967 in Introduction of Epilogue, volume I, II and III (1935, 1936, 1937) by the editor (Laura Riding)" ts. 8pp. photocopy; ts. 1p. carbon; ts. 1p. carbon [1975] (Box 95, Folder 18)
      - "Schuyler Brinkerhoof [sic] Jackson: August 18, 1900-July 4, 1968" [background material written for a memorial piece in the Princeton Alumni Weekly, Sept. 7, 1968] ts. 8pp. (Box 95, Folder 19)
      - [Note concerning] "The Art of the Moving Picture by Vachel Lindsay" ms. 3x5 card, May 1969 (Box 95, Folder 20)
      - "Instructions for Faber & Faber, 1970-- Selected Poems in Five Sets by Laura Riding" title note, ms. 1p.; ts. 8pp. (Box 95, Folder 21)
      - [Note concerning] "The Left Heresy" ms.4pp., January 1970 (Box 95, Folder 22)
      - "Commentary by Laura Riding on A Survey of Modernist Poetry to accompany the copy of the book in the Laura Riding Jackson and Schuyler B. Jackson Collection in the Department of Rare Books, Cornell University Library" ts. 4pp.; ts. 4pp. carbon ["This is a revision of December 1971 from an initial commentary of December 1964..."] " A Survey of Modernist Poetry" ts. 1p. Dec. 4, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 23)
      - [Scripts of L(R)J's corrections of Hugh Ford's successive trials for chapter in his book on private presses, X, Y, Z, October 3, 1971] ms. 145 pp.; note ms. 1p., 1971, 1972 (Box 95, Folder 24)
      - ["I did not write again to Mr. Hamburger...], Jan. 1971?, See also: Hamburger, Michael in Series III. Correspondence Laura (Riding) Jackson. Incoming. (Box 95, Folder 25)
      - "Description of The Telling in Harper & Row catalogue, (Spring) February-July 1973" ms. 4pp. (Box 95, Folder 26)
      - "Of the difficulty to which Wyndham Lewis refers..." ms. 1p.; ts. 1p.; 2ts. 1 p. carbon, October 19, 1973 (Box 95, Folder 27)
      - "[A little essay on] Anarchism Is Not Enough, 1928" 2ms. 4pp.; ms. 3pp. ["written for incorporation in a book in progress ( The Failure of Poetry/)], 1974 (Box 95, Folder 28)
      - "To the Chairman of the Seminar on 'Laura Riding and Robert Graves'--Modern Language Association, December 19[74]. A Letter of Varied Commentary from Laura (Riding) Jackson" 2ts. 4pp. photocopy "To the Chairman of the Seminar... Postscript to A Letter of Varied Commentary--written December 17, 1974" ts. 4pp. photocopy; ts. 4pp. carbon "Addenda (from postcript to A Letter to the Chairman...)" 2ts. pp. 22-23 carbon (Box 95, Folder 29)
      - "To a Friendly Correspondent of the Publishing World..." ts. 2pp., 1974., [See: Application for a John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship and report, June 24, 1974 in Series III. Correspondence. Outgoing] (Box 95, Folder 30)
      - "Further Comments on contents of Antaeus # 13/14 1974..." ts. 1p.; note ms. 1p. (Box 95, Folder 31)
      - "The treatment shows up in unexpected forms..." ts. 4pp., ca. 1975 (Box 95, Folder 32)
      - "As to Published in Paris, a book by Hugh Ford (Macmillan, NY, 1975)" ts. n.p. (Box 95, Folder 33)
      - "Comments for Dr. Donald D. Eddy's consultation..." [commentary on unpublished prose material deposited at Cornell University] (1975) ts. 5pp. carbon with corrections; ts. 5pp. (Box 95, Folder 34)
      - "To a Friend, As To America, 1975" ts. 1p.; 2ts. 1p. carbon; note ms. 1p. (Box 95, Folder 35)
      - "To a Rather New Friend" ts. 1p.; ts. 1p. carbon, Feb. 1975 (Box 95, Folder 36)
      - "As to the Early Essay A Prophecy On" ts. 1p., July 1976 (Box 95, Folder 37)
      - "To Someone, As To My Work," Sept. 1976 (Box 95, Folder 38)
      - "Some writing on A.T. Tolley's book..." (November 17, 1976) 2ts. 2pp. "Further as to the Tolley book" (November 19, 1976) ts. 2pp. (Box 95, Folder 39)
      - [On William H. Pritchard, Seeing Through Everything] ms./ts. 6pp; ms. 4pp., 1977? William H. Pritchard, Seeing Through Everything pp. 114-137, photocopy (Box 95, Folder 40)
      - "The Woolfs, Etc." ts. 2pp., ca. 1977 (Box 95, Folder 41)
      - "To Someone on Critical Avoidance of My Poetic Work" ts. 1p.; ts. 1p carbon, 1977 (Box 95, Folder 42)
      - "The Worst Wizardry" ts. 21pp.; ms. notes for revision, 1978? (Box 95, Folder 43)
      - [L(R)J's comments on the autobiographies by Thomas S. Matthews] ts. 9pp.; note ms. 1p, late 1970s "...our letting anyone have a glimpse of the course of our work..." ts. pp. 148-154, late 1970s (Box 95, Folder 44)
      - "On several references to myself appearing in the third volume of Letters of Virginia Woolf" ts. pp. 1-6, 6a, 7-23 carbon; ts. p. 8, 22, 23 carbon, 1978 (Box 96, Folder 1)
      - "Language Under Attack, Language Under Defence" ts. 10pp., 1980? (Box 96, Folder 2)
      - "Afterword" [for A Trojan Ending], ts. 8pp., 1984 (Box 96, Folder 3)
      - "Free vilification corner--Laura (Riding) Jackson" ts. 68pp., 1984 or 1985 (Box 96, Folder 4)
      - "A Design" ts. 1p., November 1985 (Box 96, Folder 5)
      - "I provide this note on this copy of Ezra Pound's Provenca..." ts. 1p., December 31, 1985 (Box 96, Folder 6)
      - "The Experience of Literature" ms. pp. 51-123, 1987? (Box 96, Folder 7)
      - "The Ends of Literature: A Collection of Miscellaneous Writings by Laura (Riding) Jackson: Introduction" ts. 14pp., mid-1980s? (Box 96, Folder 8)
      - "A Reduction" [Review of From Moon to Moon: Selected Letters of Robert Graves, edited by Paul O'Prey (Hutchinson, 1984)] ts. 5pp., mid-1980s? (Box 96, Folder 9)
      - "Passages from a portion of my memoirs treating of my membership in the group 'The Fugitives' and my relationship with it, and individual members" ts. 3pp., late 1980s (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Letters to Editors
      - The Saturday Review, May 28, 1966 ts. 3pp. carbon (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - L'Ephemere, 1969? ts. 3pp. (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The Review, November 18, 1970 ts. 2pp. carbon (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The Massachusetts Review, October 1970 ms. 11pp. (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The New York Review [of Books], July 22, 1972 ts. 2pp. (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The Times Literary Supplement, October 2, 1972 ts. 2pp. (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - The New York Review of Books, Summer 1973 ts. 3pp. (Box 96, Folder 11)